

GRADUATE RESEARCH ASSISTANT · AUTONOMOUS SYSTEMS GROUP · THE UNIVERSITY OF TEXAS AT AUSTIN

☑ fdjeumou@utexas.edu | 🌴 franckdjeumou.qithub.io | 🖸 wuwushrek | 🛅 franck-djeumou-626613202 | 📓 Franck Djeumou

Research Interests

My research aims to build learning systems that can be explained in human terms, formally verified, and can operate even with scarce amount of data. Specifically, I investigate how prior knowledge on the environment (e.g., known rules, properties validated from experiments, laws of Physics) can be incorporated into learning systems to improve the data efficiency and explainability, and how such knowledge can be used for the formal verification, particularly in the context of safety-critical applications. To this end, I develop theoretical, practical, and computational methods by drawing from diverse fields such as machine learning, deep (reinforcement) learning, formal methods, and convex/nonconvex optimization.

Education __

The University of Texas at Austin

Austin, USA

September 2018 - May 2023 (Expected)

Ph.D. IN ELECTRICAL AND COMPUTER ENGINEERING

• Ph.D. Advisor: Ufuk Topcu

• Cumulative GPA Over 30 Credits (Ph.D. Major Course Requirements): 3.96

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE AND MASTER OF SCIENCE IN AEROSPACE ENGINEERING

ISAE-SUPAERO (Institut Supérieur de l'Aéronautique et de l'Espace)

Toulouse France

September 2014 - June 2018

Advised by Prof. Jerome Hugues

- Cumulative GPA: 3.8 | Top 4% of the class
- Thesis on "Safety Guarantees for Drones through Set-Based Formal Verification Methods"

École Polytechnique Palaiseau, Franc

MASTER DEGREE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE (COMASIC)

September 2016 - September 2017

- Advised by Prof. Eric Goubault and Prof. Sylvie Putot
- Cumulative GPA: 3.7 | Graduated with Honours
- Thesis on "Human-Embedded Autonomous Flight Under Formal Task Specifications"
- This master degree was obtained as a collaboration between ISAE-SUPAERO and École Polytechnique

Lycée Fénelon Paris, France

CLASS PREPARATORY (EQUIVALENT TO JUNIOR UNDERGRADUATE LEVEL) IN MATHEMATICS, PHYSICS, AND COMPUTER SCIENCE

September 2011 - June 2014

• 6th out of 42 students

Experience

Autonomous Systems Group

Austin, USA

GRADUATE RESEARCH ASSISTANT | ADVISOR: UFUK TOPCU

September 2018 - Present

- Published 9 conference papers (with 1 paper currently under review) and 6 journal papers (with 3 papers currently under review)
- Collaborated with researchers from various international academic institutions, national research laboratories and companies, and presented
 research outcomes at more than 5 invited talks.

Cosynus Team at Laboratory LIX of École Polytechnique

Palaiseau, France

RESEARCH INTERN | ADVISORS: ERIC GOUBAULT AND SYLVIE PUTOT

March 2018 - August 2018

- Designed and Built the quadrotor testbed for the research team based on Crazyflie drones
- Implemented a hardware and software in the loop, Gazebo-based swarm simulator for the Crazyflie drones
- The code for the simulator is publicly available at www.shrek/sim_cf and has over 20 stars and 20 forks on GitHub.
- · Investigated safety of dynamical systems through Taylor-based methods and abstract interpretation
- · Investigated on-the-fly, lightweight and real-time verification (reach and safety properties) algorithms to be embedded on Crazyflie drones

Autonomous Systems Group (UT Austin)

Austin, USA

RESEARCH INTERN | ADVISOR: UFUK TOPCU

March 2017 - August 2017

- Designed and built quadrotors based on the Snapdragon Platform and PX4 as the autopilot. Implemented a fast trajectory generator for quadrotors based on the minimum snap approach via a new problem modeling
- Investigated human interface with virtual reality and autonomous flight of a quadrotor via eye-tracking (youtube.com/watch?v=AfosHcUJR9M)
- Investigated the problem of tracking moving targets using POMDPs (Partially Observable Markov Decision Process) and human inputs
- Designed model checking and planning algorithms for UAVs autonomous missions with specifications expressed in temporal logic

Liebherr Aerospace and Transportation

Toulouse, France

June 2015 - August 2015

Machine Learning Intern

- Implementation in R of supervised learning algorithms to automatically classify aircraft's equipments from a reliability point of view
- Designed and implemented an application in Java that interacts with Liebherr's database to provide classification results to an expert



French (native), English (fluent), Japanese (beginner) Languages

Python, C++, C, Java, C#, R, Matlab, HTML5/CSS3 | My GitHub stats estimate more than 100k lines of code **Programming**

Tools & Technologies ROS, JAX, TensorFlow, Unity, Gazebo, PX4 Autopilot, Crazyflie, MuJoCo, RTOS, CVXPY, Gurobi, Mosek, Arduino

> Sports Tennis, Soccer, Running, Biking, Skiing

Publications

* indicates equal contribution

PEER-REVIEWED CONFERENCE ARTICLES [9]

Taylor-Lagrange Neural Ordinary Differential Equations: Toward Fast Training and Evaluation of Neural ODEs

Franck Djeumou*, Cyrus Neary*, Eric Goubault, Sylvie Putot, Ufuk Topcu

Under Review at International Joint Conferences on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI) 2022

URL: https://arxiv.org/abs/2201.05715

2022

Neural Networks with Physics-Informed Architectures and Constraints for Dynamical Systems Modeling

Franck Djeumou*, Cyrus Neary*, Eric Goubault, Sylvie Putot, Ufuk Topcu

Accepted at Learning for Dynamics and Control Conference (L4DC) 2022

URL: https://arxiv.org/abs/2109.06407

Task-Guided Inverse Reinforcement Learning Under Partial Information

Franck Djeumou, Murat Cubuktepe, Craig Lennon, Ufuk Topcu Accepted at International Conference on Automated Planning and Scheduling (ICAPS) 2022

2021 URL: https://arxiv.org/abs/2105.14073

Learning to Reach, Swim, Walk and Fly in One Trial: Data-Driven Control with Scarce Data and Side Information

Franck Djeumou, Ufuk Topcu

Accepted at Learning for Dynamics and Control Conference (L4DC) 2022

URL: https://arxiv.org/abs/2106.10533

Blending Controllers via Multi-Objective Bandits

Parham Gohari*, Franck Djeumou*, Abraham P Vinod, Ufuk Topcu

Accepted at the 2022 American Control Conference (ACC) as an invited paper

URL: https://arxiv.org/abs/2007.15755 2021

Learning-Based, Safety-Constrained Control from Scarce Data via Reciprocal Barriers

Christos K Verginis, Franck Djeumou, Ufuk Topcu

IEEE Conference on Decision and Control

URL: https://cverginis.github.io/publications/conferences/CDC21_safety.pdf

On-the-fly, Data-driven Reachability Analysis and Control of Unknown Systems: An F-16 Aircraft Case Study (Best Demo/Poster Award) Franck Djeumou, Aditya Zutshi, Ufuk Topcu

International Conference on Hybrid Systems: Computation and Control (HSCC 2021)

URL: https://dl.acm.org/doi/abs/10.1145/3447928.3457355

On-The-Fly Control of Unknown Smooth Systems from Limited Data

Franck Djeumou, Abraham P. Vinod, Éric Goubault, Sylvie Putot, Ufuk Topcu

2021 American Control Conference (ACC)

URL: https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9483367

Probabilistic Swarm Guidance Subject to Graph Temporal Logic Specifications

Franck Djeumou, Zhe Xu, Ufuk Topcu

Robotics: Science and Systems (RSS)

 $\verb|URL: http://www.roboticsproceedings.org/rss16/p058.pdf|\\$

JOURNAL ARTICLES [6]

Task-Guided IRL on POMDPs at Scale with Information Asymmetry

Franck Djeumou, Christian Ellis, Murat Cubuktepe, Craig Lennon, Ufuk Topcu

Under Review at the special issue VSI:Risk-Aware Autonomy for consideration at the journal of Artificial Intelligence (2022). Elsevier

Probabilistic Control of Heterogeneous Swarms Subject to Graph Temporal Logic Specifications: A Decentralized and Scalable Approach

Franck Djeumou, Zhe Xu, Murat Cubuktepe, Ufuk Topcu Conditionally accepted at IEEE Transactions on Automatic Control (IEE TAC) (2021). IEEE

URL: https://arxiv.org/abs/2106.15729

Safety-Constrained Learning and Control using Scarce Data and Reciprocal Barriers

Christos K Verginis, Franck Djeumou, Ufuk Topcu

Under Review at IEEE Transactions on Automatic Control (2021). IEEE

URL: https://arxiv.org/abs/2105.06526

On-The-Fly Control of Unknown Systems: From Side Information to Performance Guarantees through Reachability

Franck Djeumou, Abraham P Vinod, Eric Goubault, Sylvie Putot, Ufuk Topcu

Conditionally accepted at IEEE Transactions on Automatic Control (2021). IEEE

URL: https://arxiv.org/abs/2011.05524

Policy Synthesis for Switched Linear Systems with Markov Decision Process Switching

Bo Wu, Murat Cubuktepe, Franck Djeumou, Zhe Xu, Ufuk Topcu

2021

2021

URL: https://arxiv.org/abs/2009.12733

Online Synthesis for Runtime Enforcement of Safety in Multi-Agent Systems

Dhananjay Raju, Sudarshanan Bharadwaj, Franck Djeumou, Ufuk Topcu

IEEE Transactions on Control of Network Systems (2021). IEEE

URL: https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9362272

2021

Honors & Awards

2021	Winner , Best Demo/Poster Award at Proceedings of the 24th International Conference on Hybrid Systems:	Nashville, USA
2021	Computation and Control (HSCC 2021)	
2017	Scholarship, Foundation of Ecole Polytechnique	Palaiseau, France
2017	Scholarship, ISAE-SUPAERO Foundation	Toulouse, France
2016	Scholarship, ISAE-SUPAERO Foundation	Toulouse, France
2015	Scholarship, ISAE-SUPAERO Foundation	Toulouse, France
2014	Scholarship, ISAE-SUPAERO Foundation	Toulouse, France

Professional Services

WORKSHOPS ORGANIZED

Workshop on Safe and Reliable Robot Autonomy under Uncertainty

Philadelphia, USA

May 2022

Co-organizer

REVIEWER

I was a reviewer at the following journals and conferences.

INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON ROBOTICS AND AUTOMATION (ICRA)

- IEEE Transactions on Automatic Control (2021)
- International Conference on Robotics and Automation (2021)
- American Control Conference (2020, 2021)
- IEEE Conference on Decision and Control (2021)
- IFAC symposium system identification (2021)

Invited Talks____

2021	Incorporating Physics-Based Knowledge into Neural Network Dynamics Models, Galois Inc: Final Briefing for the Assured Autonomy Project	Austin, USA
2021	Learning How to Reach, Swim, Walk and Fly in One Trial, Professor Karen E. Willcox's Research Group	Austin, USA
2021	How to learn to reach, walk, swim and fly in one trial? Well, first, admit that you are not dumb, Lockheed Martin	Austin, USA
2021	How to learn to reach, walk, swim and fly in one trial? Well, first, admit that you are not dumb, Texas Robotics Symposium	Austin, USA
2021	Data-Driven, On-The-Fly Reachability and Control of Unknown Systems, Mini-Symposium on "Leaning for Dynamical Systems and Control" at the SIAM Conference on Applications of Dynamical Systems	Portland, USA
2020	Learning On-the-Fly with a Case Study in Hypersonic Flight, Sandia National Laboratories: Autonomy for Hypersonics Virtual Field Day	Austin, USA

References ____

- · Prof. Ufuk Topcu, Assistant Professor (Controls, Autonomy and Robotics), The University of Texas at Austin, USA
- Prof. Eric Goubault, Professor (Computer Science), École Polytechnique, France
- Prof. Sylvie Putot, Professor (Computer Science), École Polytechnique, France